Peter Kohler

Chicago, Illinois, United States



peterkohler95@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/peter-kohler

Summary

Software engineer with experience in the healthcare and financial services industries. Biomedical Engineering major from the University of Miami with a passion for helping others through technology. With an engineering mindset, I want to develop software that has a real impact on improving people's lives.

Technical Skills: Java, Spring, Javascript, React, Redux, Python, Django, RESTful APIs, MySQL, AWS

Soft Skills: Communication, Problem Solving, Leadership, Teamwork, Adaptability

Experience



Co-Founder

Prismatic

Jul 2021 - Present (7 months +)

Technical Analyst

Kin + Carta

Mar 2019 - Jul 2021 (2 years 5 months)

cp Software Developer

Coinplan

Nov 2018 - Mar 2019 (5 months)

- Securely integrated firebase user authentication to store login information for our growing user base which helped us launch our MVP
- Designed and implemented scalable Cloud Firestore database schema to securely store data for our currently 190 users
- Help design and build an aesthetically pleasing front end and am currently working on implement react native mobile app



Associate Quality Assurance Engineer

Medline Industries, LP

Jan 2018 - May 2018 (5 months)

- Assisted my department in becoming the most profitable that quarter by launching a new bath safety product line and assuring that FDA regulations were adhered to.
- Developed project management software using Excel macros, leading to an increase in team organization and productivity
- Advised the product team regarding concepts for new couch assist product in order to stay competitive in the marketplace

Education

University of Miami

Bachelor of Science - BS, Biomedical/Medical Engineering 2013 - 2017

Licenses & Certifications

☐ CFCD: Cloud Foundry Certified Developer - The Linux Foundation

Issued Jul 2019 - Expires Jul 2020

G Google Associate Cloud Engineer - Google

Issued Jan 2020 - Expires Jan 2022

Amazon Web Services Cloud Practitioner - Amazon Web Services (AWS)

Issued Feb 2020 - Expires Feb 2023

Skills

React.js • Redux.js • JavaScript • Engineering • Research • Social Media • Web Development • Project Management • Software Development • Data Analysis